R. Scott Vivilecchia

DEMO REEL - https://vi-vi.io/reel

P Bourne, MA

4. 617-678-4222

▼ rscott@vi-vi.io

∠ https://vi-vi.io

Summary

A Visual Storyteller with demonstrated experience delivering poignant, strategy-driven video content. I'm proficient in concept development, pre-production planning, editing, animation/motion graphics, color grading, and sound design. As a seasoned, independent professional, experienced working with high-profile corporate and government clients, I'm dedicated to providing top-notch solutions, throughout the production process, ensuring that the outcome meets or exceeds initiative goals.

I bring thought leadership, a sense of adventure, and roll-up-the-sleeves tenacity to every project I work on.

Skill Highlights

Story-boarding, strategy, scripting

Color Grading

Illustration / Graphic Design

Mobile-first UI/UX design

Video Editing

Al enhanced workflow

Premiere Pro / After Effects

Front-end web code fluent

Motion Graphics / Animation

Interviewing, Directing & Camera-op

Davinci Resolve 18

Mac, Windows & Linux

Experience

Filmmaker and Creative Media Consultant – Independent Freelancer July 2019 - Present

Use thoughtful storytelling, a well-honed research process, and compassion for subject / talent, to craft captivating, candid video messaging for business in a variety of industries, as well as government and not-for-profit entities

Demonstrated experience in documentary, corporate messaging, education, and journalistic genres

An editor with strong understanding of trends and tech requirements for social platforms, leading to deeper engagement and CTA follow-through

A skilled studio and on-location Director / DP / Videographer, experienced with modern equipment and techniques

Recent clients and collaborations - Transdev, Inotiv, Triple M, Upgrad, PACTV

Video Production Specialist - Voya Financial

March 2013 - July 2019

Collaborated with Fortune 500 and large government clients, on custom-branded, award-winning educational videos that clarified complex investment topics, and drove engagement within a variety of unique employee benefit plans

Worked with the executive leadership team to plan and produce engaging, meaningful video content, adhering to and helping to evolve Voya's brand standards

Creative Services Designer – Voya Financial, ING, CitiStreet August 2004 – March 2013

Provide strategic and creative support for Mega and Large market Institutional and government sales efforts, including production of videos and custom web apps to introduce the team and highlight capabilities

Education

Ongoing Professional Development - Recent courses

Philip Bloom's Cinematic Master Class - MZed.com

Color Grading and Motion Graphics with Davinci Resolve - Filmsimplified.com

Art Institute of Boston, Boston, MA – B.F.A. Graphic Design

1998 - 2001

County College of Morris, Randolph, NJ – A.A. Graphic Design 1996 - 1998

Links

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/vi-vi-io/

Vimeo

https://vimeo.com/user113004102

Portfolio/Self-promo Page

https://www.vi-vi.io/